Where are you, Sir Kimblee?!
This is far from what you promised!
You said your soldiers in Briggs would betray the others if we were to carry the attack to the fort!
Cease fire!
That was a crushing victory.
Yeah.
So this...
...is the bloody crest.
We sigh whenever we're about to come to a standstill
Owarinaki tabi no tochuu tachidomarisouna toki
While moving on this endless journey.
Fukai tameiki kobosu bokura wa
Everytime we lunge for it, it escapes and flies off.
Tsukamikaketewa mata hanareteitta
But now, there's nothing to be afraid of
Demo ima wa mou nanimo osoreru koto wa nai
The powerful ties that bind our hearts
Kokoro wo tsunagu tsuyoi kizuna wa
Will never come loose.
Keshite hodoke wa shinai sa
After a lifetime of searching, we finally arrived
Sagashitsuzukete tadoritsuita
Here, where the period lies.
Kono basho de piriodo ni
Let's change all our sorrow and rage to power.
Kanashimi ikari chikara ni kaete
Destiny is right within our reach.
Unmei wa sugu soba ni
So I'm saying...
...you're supposed to read the veins of the dragon while performing Eastern Alchemy!
And I'm saying...
...I don't understand how!
You're supposed to sharpen your senses!
Ready, go!
See? I sense it!
I can't do that!
Yes, you can!
Teach me the theories behind it!
Things are real rowdy in there.
I don't get it!
Sorry for having to ask you to hide us here.
Hey, don't worry about it.
We're benefiting as well.
Not the hair!
Now the kids have someone new to play with.
Let Zampano know that we're going up to the mountains to collect firewood.
Sure.
Damn it!
What a nightmare!
Where the hell is Zampano?! Everyone else is working!
Yo!
This way.
Follow me.
I'm counting on you, Zampano.
Bite of the Ant
So, you found out about Selim.
Yes.
And my identity, as well.
How do you feel as a citizen of a country...
...to know that your leader and his son are both Homunculi?
I believe it's a very sad thing for a family member you're supposed to trust to be fabricated.
It's almost like you're playing house.
All the while pretending to be human, creatures you deem as fools.
As you say, he's my "son" given to me by my handlers.
My rank of Führer President, along with my men and everything else, was also given to me.
Rather than "house", I'd say it's more accurate to say we're playing "politics".
However, I picked my bride myself.
Is the tea still not ready?
P-Pardon me.
Delicious.
Wow, so you used to be one of the head honchos of that Research Laboratory 5.
I wouldn't say that. I just had a couple of people working under me.
I wonder how they're doing now...
Hey!
Who might that be?
He's a vagrant I met this morning.
He wanted to have you see him, Doctor-
That's enough, Zampano.
The shitty acting ends here.
Why hello, Doctor.
What might you be doing here?
You're being too optimistic if you think roaches like you can outwit us.
What the hell is this?!
Zampano!
The shitty acting ends here, right?!
Our goal from the start was to lure you here!
Knowing how much of a nasty guy you are,
I figured you'd come and hunt me yourself if you knew I was alive!
What can three pieces of trash like you do?!
No matter how many you've got on your side,
you're nothing but trash in the end-
They work like landmines.
Alchemy evolves every day!
There's no way alchemy like that can exist-
Dammit!
If they're mines...
...all I have to do is trace your footsteps!
How can this be?!
They were made to only react to Homunculi!
You can't tell where they are and what awaits you because of all the snow.
So, tell me.
How does it feel to be ridiculed by people
you've been looking down on as trash and scum?
He's being fooled, all right.
It's just remote alchemy.
You bastards!
You scum should obey our commands, just as you were meant to!
You're nothing but trash! Don't get too cocky!
Doctor!
That was close.
Th-Thanks.
Grr. You're pretty fast for a fatass.
Don't underestimate trash!
You little shit!!
Such weak attacks can hardly pierce my skin!
Is that so?
Then what about this ?!
Did he do it?!
Got you now!
Doctor!
Whoa, don't move.
If you do, I'll snap him in half.
Now...
...you're in for some punishment.
Didn't I warn you, Doctor?
By saying I'll destroy an entire village if you were to do something unnecessary?
I won't let you!
You're still going to resist?
Man, you're dumb.
Okay, I'll destroy those slums over there.
Stop!
But simply destroying them is no fun.
Perhaps I'll bring a few back to Central and make a philosopher's stone out of them.
You filth!
You're still making those things over at Central?!
Release the researchers...
Release my men!
Huh?
That's impossible.
Because you see, we've already turned all of them into philosopher's stones.
E-Even my men?!
Oh? Guess I forgot to tell you, huh?
But Doctor, you shouldn't have any reason to weep now , after all this time.
Since you've made so many philosopher's stones in the past.
Using human lives.
You're right.
I've made many philosopher's stones, sacrificing the lives of many people.
I am more familiar with the ways of making a
philosopher's stone than anyone else in this country.
Knowing how to make one...
...also means I know how to destroy them!!
What on earth is that?!
It's coming from the hill where the doctor and the others are!
Oww! Oww!
Oww! Oww! Ow! Ow!
No...
It hurts!
This is...
No...
This-
This can't be...
I'm Envy...
There's no way I could be defeated by you inferior beings...
No...
Even the chimeras...
Don't look at me...
D-Don't look at-
Don't look down on me, humans!!!
Don't look at me, you insects...
Little shits...
Don't... look...
We were being manipulated by something like this ?
We won, Marcoh.
They're back!
Doctor Marcoh! What's with that wound?!
What's that ?
Wow, so you guys were doing some amazing things without us knowing.
This is what happens when you disobey us humans!
Why did you do something so reckless, Doctor Marcoh?
All my life, I've been doing everything as ordered.
But this was the one thing I wanted to settle myself.
Thinking on my own... Making a decision on my own...
Just like your parents did things.
But please, try not to be so reckless.
Okay.
Oww!!
Ow! Ow! Ow! Ow! Ow!
Sir Yoki?
H-Help me...
I've taken over this guy's body!
Stop!
You monster!
M-My body isn't listening to me!
No use putting up a fight!
Now, you trash!
If you want to help this guy...
Nah, you can do whatever you want with him.
He's not really our friend, anyway.
It's been a short while, Sir Yoki...
I'll never forget you!
Master Scar!
You're  on my side though, right?!
Right?!
Don't look away, dammit!!
I believed in you, Master!
W-What? I thought this guy was your friend!
I believed in you!
Quit putting up a useless fight, Envy!
At this point, we don't exactly care about our actions.
If you're going to get in our way,
we'll destroy you along with that man!
Dammit...
He came off.
Really?
Nice act.
I-I'm not very good at bluffs...
Damn you all!
None of you are my friends!
Our friendship is over!
I have nothing to do with you anymore!
Damn...
So, it's about time you tell us what you guys are up to.
Like I'll tell you.
What did you say?!
Spill it!
Spill the beans, you insect!
Keep it up!
Show him who's boss, Zampano!
If I tell you, I'll just be killed later!
Why would I tell you, idiots?
You son of a...
Oh yeah, where's the Fullmetal runt?
Brother?
He should be in Briggs right now.
Oh?
Last I heard, he was missing.
What?!
What do you mean?!
Tell me more!
I heard a mine collapsed in Baschool.
I wonder if he's alive...
No way...
That can't be true.
So, what should we do?
Should we head back to Baschool?
No.
In a situation like this...
...Brother would definitely believe in the safety of the other team and keep moving forward.
So I want to do the same.
Hope is not lost.
I'm going to split off for a bit.
I've been thinking about it for a little while now.
Instead of simply detesting this country for denying Ishbal...
...I'm going to work to change it.
And for that, I need your help as well, Marcoh.
Sure.
I'll go with you.
To change this country...
The thing is, there's a city I want to visit, as well.
Where?
Lior.
If my predictions are correct, that tunnel should be there, too.
May, take this thing and return to your country.
So I'm thinking it'll be fastest for us to just destroy that.
Then, we'll be able to buy time.
Hey, Master!
It's the wreck of an immortal homunculus.
With the extra time, we can solve the structure of the new transmutation circle.
With this, your clan may be saved.
So, this "new transmutation circle" is the thing we discovered the other day, right?
B-But if I go back, who'll be here to help you with Eastern Alchemy-
Yup, that's the one.
Is this really the time to be worrying about another country?!
Did you come to this country with a resolve that weak?
If your clan happens to lose its struggle for power,
what are you going to tell the people who placed their fate in your hands?
"I failed because I was too busy helping people from another country"?!
Go.
We, the citizens of this country, will take care of it ourselves.
Thank you... so much!
Take care, May.
Once we settle things here, I'll visit you to learn more about Eastern Alchemy.
Sir Al...
Sir Al!
I... I...
Thank you so much, everyone!
Good bye!
Take care!
She's gone...
Yeah.
Well then, we should get going, as well.
Right.
Mr. Greed...
No luck.
Apparently, Izumi Curtis is out on vacation with her husband, and no one knows when they'll be back.
Guess there's not much we can do.
We should head back and report this to Führer President Bradley for now.
Bradley?!
You're coming with me, Greed.
Call someone to take over.
Good idea.
I might be able to see Mr. Greed if I follow them...
But...
Umm...
Would you mind moving your foot, Sister?
You are to address me as "Major General" here!
Aye, ma'am!
You've got a cowardly face on as always, I see.
I heard the battle with Drachma ended with your crushing victory.
Of course!
But wouldn't that just speed up the completion of the Nationwide Transmutation Circle?
It doesn't matter.
What we must protect right now is the safety of the country itself.
If there stands an enemy who threatens that very peace...
...our job is to deliver an overwhelming defeat of perfection!
Oh dear... why must you act so fierce?
At this rate, you'll never find someone to marry-
You just lack the fighting spirit!
You laggard!
Being with you makes me feel cowardly as well!
There you are, Major General.
He's your brother, I take it?
I don't even want to think of him as my brother.
He's a coward who ran away from Ishbal.
Follow me.
There's something I'd like to show you.
Are you aware of the three laws state alchemists are forbidden to disobey?
If I recall...
"Do not oppose the military."
"Do not make gold."
And "Do not create humans."
Precisely.
The first law is self-explanatory.
The second law is put in place to avoid economic turmoil.
Then what about the third?
Why does the nation forbid alchemists from creating humans?
I assume it's because of the moral and ethical implications.
Even among alchemists, I hear the act is tacitly forbidden as a blasphemy to God.
You're wrong there.
What is and is not ethical changes with time and also depends on whom you ask.
That is not the reason.
It is to prevent an individual from creating a powerful army of their own, Major General.
The promise we never made
Kawashita hazu no nai yakasoku ga
yet again
Kyou mo
tries to snatch our future away from us.
Bokura no mirai wo ubaou to suru
Why is it that we can't rejoice
Hoshigatteita mono wo te ni shitemo
straight from the heart
Sunao ni
when we obtain something we've always been after?
Umaku waraenai nowa nazedarou
The overflowing tears aren't from feebleness or remorse.
Afureru namida wo yowasa ya koukai ja nai
They're fragments born from agony.
Itami ga unda kakera de
Of all the moments and destinies,
Donna shunkan datte unmei datte
I realized there's one absolute certainty.
Hitotsu dake tashika na mono ga aru to shitta
Even if things get tough and I'm at my limit
Genkai datte konnan datte
I refuse to give up.
Akirametakunaiyo
Please, don't let go.
Konomama hanasanaide
I can feel the warmth of your right hand
Kataku nigirishimeta kimi no migite no nukumori
where it's tightly joined with my left.
Koko ni arukara
This place is in ruins...
Is there really a place to eat around here?
Let's see... I know it was around here somewhere...
Rose!
How have you been?!
I should be asking you the same thing, Al!
What, you're still on a journey?
Oh, you know her?
Yeah, something like that.
Al, where's Ed?
He's not with you?
B-Brother isn't with us today.
Oh... that's too bad.
I really wanted to see him.
What's this?
Wh-What?!
No, I was just pondering the meaning behind that mysterious look on your face.
Quit saying weird things!
Hey, Rose!
I finished washing the pots!
Is there anything else for me to-
Reunion. Revival. Resolve.
The time has come to set the soul afire.
As long as they live, humans continue to move forward.
No matter how thorny the path may be.
Next time, Fullmetal Alchemist:
Episode 44, Revving at Full Throttle.
Revving at Full Throttle
Awaken, human.
Now is the beginning.